A Finding Aid to the Erle Loran Papers, 1912-1999, in the Archives of American Art AAA.loraerle
Archives of American Art
- Writings, 1921-1999; Series 4; (Boxes 3-4; 1.25 linear feet)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1957-1984 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Mark Tobey, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - A Memorandum to President Sproul and the Regents of the University, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Modern Ideas in Education, circa 1920s (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Modernism in Northern California, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - [Non-objective Art], circa 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - [Notes], circa 1950s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - [Notes on African Art], circa 1950s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - The Notes of an Antique [Vessel?], 1922 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Notes on Cézanne, circa 1950s (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - [Notes on Cézanne], circa 1930s-1950s (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - [Notes on Hans Hofmann], circa 1950s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - [On Abstraction], circa 1960s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - [On African Sculpture], circa 1950s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - [On Art and Meaning], 1940s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - [On California Art Schools], circa 1950s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - [On Cameron Booth], circa 1940s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - [On Cézanne], circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - [On Clyfford Still], circa 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - [On Contemporary Art], circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - [On Disputed CézannePainting], circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - [On Form and Composition], circa 1950s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - [On Form and Invention], circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - [On Hans Hofmann], circa 1965 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - [On Hippies], circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - [On Learning With Hans Hofmann], 1954 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - [On Marsden Hartley], circa 1950s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - [On Painting], circa 1950s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - [On Psychology and Gender In Art], circa 1950s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - [On the Body], circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - [On Writing About Art], circa 1950s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Painting, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Pathway to Pavillon Cézanne, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Paul Cézanne, circa 1952 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Paul Cézanne1839-1906, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Paul Cézanne1839-1906, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Paul CézanneAccording to Ambroise Vollard, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - The Plastic Means, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Pleasures and Perils of Collecting, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Pop Art, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Problems of the Modern Artist, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Qualities of an Actor, circa 1920s (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Remembering Marsden Hartley, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Statement on African Art, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Symbology, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Symbology in Abstract Art, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Symbology in Non-Objective Painting, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Titian, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - [To Hans Hofmann on Cézanne], circa 1940s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Two Kinds of Form, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Two Still Lives By Cézanne, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - The Value of Costumes and Scenery, circa 1920s (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - The Well in the Forest of the Chateau Noir, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - What a Newspaper Means to a Boy, circa 1920s (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Writings by Others (Box 4)
    - [Review of CézanneComposition] by Donald Bear, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - [Quotation From William Blake], circa 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - [Cézanneas a Classic Master], circa 1950s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Cézanne's Life and Work, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Cézanne's Work, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - The Inspired Pretenders by Herman Cherry, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Kyle Morris by Herman Cherry, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - What He Said to Me: the Motive, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - [Artist Statement] by R.T. Gordon, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - On Hearing a Lecture on Cézanneby E.H., late 1970s (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - [Address] by Hans Hofmann, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Statements and Criticisms by Hans Hofmann, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Hofmann/Loran, circa 1963 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - [Recommendation For Erle Loran] by Walter Horn, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Art Education by Karl Kasten, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - But Don't Call it Intuition by Karl Kasten, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - In Memoriam - Erle Loran by Karl Kasten, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - [Tribute to Erle Loran] by [Karl Kasten?], circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Le Dimanche Avec Paul Cézanneby Leo Larquier, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - [Literary Quotations], circa 1930s-1940s (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Remembrances of Joseph B. Wheelwright by Clyta Loran, late 1970s (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - [Quotations on French History and Culture] by E.J. Lowell, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - [Quotations on Erle Loran], circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Monument to an Unknown Artist by James Rosen, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Proposal For an Interdisciplinary Doctoral Program by Antonio Ruvolo, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - [Quotation From Othello], circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Six Artists, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Statement by Clyfford Still, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 87)
- Artwork, 1920s-1980s; Series 5; (Boxes 4-8, 13-14; 4.3 linear feet)
  Over four linear feet of artwork by Loran consists primarily of preliminary drawings and sketches in watercolor, pastels, charcoal, pencil, gouache, and oil. The artwork is mostly landscape and urbanscape, abstract, and fantasy imagery. Of special interest are self portraits, and portraits of Loran's second wife, Clyta.
  Series also includes a small amount of artwork by others, including Stanley William Hayter and Alcopley.
  Found in a disorganized state, these materials have been arranged under broad categories that do not represent Loran's own organization. Due to the fragility of these materials, items have been extensively interleaved. Photographs that were found filed with a piece of art and are clearly the basis for that artwork have been kept together.
  - Aerial Views, circa 1970s-1980s; (23 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 4, Folder 88-110)
  - After Cézanne, circa 1930s-1940s; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 111-112)
  - Animals, circa 1920s-1930s; (see also Box 13) (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - Animals, circa 1930s-1960s; (see also Box 13) (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - Automobiles, circa 1920s-1940s (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - Buddha, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - CézanneDiagrams, circa 1940s; (23 folders) (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - Charcoal Sketches, circa 1930s-1960s; (27 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 4, Folder 118-144)
  - Charcoal Sketches, circa 1930s-1970s; (21 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 4, Folder 145-165)
  - Clyta Loran, circa 1930s-1940s; (5 folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-5)
  - Collage, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Fantasy Scenes, circa 1930s-1950s; (see also Box 13) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Fantasy Scenes, circa 1940s; (5 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 5, Folder 8-12)
  - Fantasy Scenes, circa 1940s-1950s; (7 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 5, Folder 13-19)
  - Fantasy Scenes, circa 1940s-1960s; (see also Box 13) (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Gouaches, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Gouaches, circa 1960s; (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 22-24)
  - Gouaches, circa 1960s-1970s; (9 folders) (Box 5, Folder 25-33)
  - Gouaches, circa 1970s (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Juvenilia, circa 1910s-1920s (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Landscapes, circa 1930s-1950s; (35 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 5, Folder 36-70)
  - Landscapes, circa 1930s-1960s; (18 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 5, Folder 71-88)
  - Landscapes, circa 1930s-1970s; (6 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 5, Folder 89-94)
  - Landscapes, circa 1940s-1950s; (see also Box 13) (Box 5, Folder 95)
  - Landscapes, circa 1940s-1980s; (see also Box 13) (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - Landscapes, circa 1950s-1970s; (5 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 5, Folder 97-101)
  - Landscapes, circa 1950s-1980s; (see also Box 13) (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - Landscapes, circa 1960s-1980s; (7 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 5, Folder 103-109)
  - Mixed Media, circa 1930s-1960s; (2 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 5, Folder 110-111)
  - Mixed Media, circa 1940s-1960s; (2 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 5, Folder 112-113)
  - Mixed Media, circa 1940s-1960s; (8 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 6, Folder 1-8)
  - Mixed Media, circa 1940s-1970s; (see also Box 13) (Box 6, Folder 9-21)
  - Mixed Media, circa 1950s-1960s; (9 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 6, Folder 22-30)
  - Mixed Media, circa 1950s-1970s; (see also Box 13) (Box 6, Folder 31-39)
  - Nudes, circa 1930s-1940s; (see also Box 13) (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Nudes, circa 1930s-1950s; (2 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 6, Folder 41-42)
  - Nudes, circa 1930s-1960s; (2 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 6, Folder 43-44)
  - Nudes, circa 1940s-1960s; (2 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 6, Folder 45-46)
  - Oil Sketches, circa 1930s-1960s (Box 6, Folder 47-48)
  - Oil Sketches, circa 1930s-1970s (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Pastel Sketches, circa 1930s-1960s; (2 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 6, Folder 50-51)
  - Pastel Sketches, circa 1930s-1970s; (3 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 6, Folder 52-54)
  - Pastel Sketches, circa 1940s-1960s; (9 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 6, Folder 55-63)
  - Pastel Sketches, circa 1940s-1970s; (4 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 6, Folder 64-67)
  - Pastel Sketches, circa 1950s-1960s; (see also Box 13) (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Pastel Sketches, circa 1950s-1970s; (5 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 6, Folder 69-73)
  - Pastel Sketches, circa 1960s-1970s; (9 folders) (Box 6, Folder 74-82)
  - Pen Sketches, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - Pen Sketches, circa 1930s-1950s; (10 folders) (Box 6, Folder 84-93)
  - Pen Sketches, circa 1930s-1960s; (11 folders) (Box 6, Folder 94-104)
  - Pen Sketches, circa 1930s-1980s (Box 6, Folder 105)
  - Pen Sketches, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 6, Folder 106)
  - Pen Sketches, circa 1960s-1980s; (6 folders) (Box 6, Folder 107-112)
  - Pencil Sketches, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 6, Folder 113)
  - Pencil Sketches, circa 1920s-1960s (Box 6, Folder 114)
  - Pencil Sketches, circa 1930s-1950s; (5 folders) (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
  - Pencil Sketches, circa 1930s-1960s; (5 folders) (Box 7, Folder 6-10)
  - Pencil Sketches, circa 1930s-1980s; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
  - Petroglyphs, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Portraits, circa 1930s-1940s; (see also Box 13) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Potraits, circa 1930s-1950s; (4 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 7, Folder 15-18)
  - Portraits, circa 1930s-1960s; (5 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 7, Folder 19-23)
  - Rural Scenes, circa 1930s-1950s; (54 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 7, Folder 24-77)
  - Rural Scenes, circa 1930s-1960s; (4 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 7, Folder 78-81)
  - Self-Portraits, circa 1930s; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 82-83)
  - Self-Portraits, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Ships, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Silhouettes, circa 1930s-1960s (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Sketchbooks, circa 1920s-1940s; (see also Box 13) (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Sketchbooks, circa 1930s-1950s; (6 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 7, Folder 88-93)
  - Sketchbooks, circa 1930s-1960s; (see also Box 13) (Box 7, Folder 94)
  - Sketchbooks, circa 1940s-1950s; (2 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 7, Folder 95-96)
  - Sketchbooks, circa 1940s-1960s; (2 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 7, Folder 97-98)
  - Sketches of Artwork, circa 1930s-1970s (Box 7, Folder 99)
  - Still Lifes, circa 1930s-1960s (Box 7, Folder 100)
  - Stencils, circa 1930s-1960s (Box 7, Folder 101)
  - Urban Scenes, circa 1930s-1950s; (12 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 7, Folder 102-113)
  - Urban Scenes, circa 1930s-1960s; (2 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 7, Folder 114-115)
  - Watercolors, circa 1930s-1950s; (2 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 7, Folder 116-117)
  - Watercolors, circa 1930s-1960s; (see also Box 13) (Box 7, Folder 118)
  - Watercolors, circa 1930s-1980s; (see also Box 13) (Box 7, Folder 119)
  - Watercolors, circa 1940s-1960s; (2 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 7, Folder 120-121)
  - Watercolors, circa 1940s-1970s; (4 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 7, Folder 122-125)
  - Watercolors, circa 1940s-1980s; (8 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 8, Folder 1-8)
  - Watercolors, circa 1950s-1980s; (4 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 8, Folder 9-12)
  - Watercolors, circa 1950s-1960s; (12 folders; see also Box 13) (Box 8, Folder 13-24)
  - Waterfront, circa 1930s-1960s (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Working, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 8, Folder 26-27)
  - Artwork By Others, 1940-1967 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    (Stanley William Hayter)
  - Artwork By Others, 1978-1980 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Artwork By Relatives[?], circa 1960s-1980s (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Aerial Views, circa 1970s-1980s; (see also Box 4) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 1)
  - Animals, circa 1930s-1950s; (see also Box 4) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 2)
  - Charcoal Sketches, circa 1930s-1950s; (4 folders) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 3-6)
  - Fantasy Scenes, circa 1940s; (see also Box 5) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 7)
  - Landscapes, circa 1930s-1950s; (5 folders; see also Box 5) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 8-12)
  - Landscapes, circa 1930s-1970s; (see also Box 5) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 13)
  - Landscapes, circa 1930s-1980s; (see also Box 5) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 14)
  - Landscapes, circa 1940s-1980s; (see also Box 5) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 15)
  - Landscapes, circa 1960s-1980s; (see also Box 5) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 16)
  - Mixed Media, circa 1930s-1950s; (see also Box 5) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 17)
  - Mixed Media, circa 1930s-1960s; (see also Box 5) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 18)
  - Mixed Media, circa 1940s-1960s; (see also Boxes 5-6) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 19)
  - Nudes, circa 1930s-1950s; (see also Box 6) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 20)
  - Pastel Sketches, circa 1930s-1950s; (see also Box 6) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 21)
  - Portraits, circa 1930s-1960s; (see also Box 7) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 22)
  - Rural Scenes, circa 1930s-1950s; (6 folders; see also Box 7) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 23-28)
  - Sketchbooks, circa 1930s-1950s; (see also Box 7) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 29)
  - Urban Scenes, circa 1930s-1950s; (2 folders; see also Box 7) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 30-31)
  - Watercolors, circa 1930s-1950s; (2 folders; see also Box 7) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 32-33)
  - Watercolors, circa 1950s-1980s; (see also Box 8) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 34)
  - Artwork By Others, circa 1950s-1970s; (Pottery Shard) (Box 14 (sol), Folder 1)
- Printed Materials, 1925-1999; Series 6; (Box 8-10, 14; 2.3 linear feet)
  Found here are clippings, exhibition announcements, and exhibition catalogs on a wide variety of topics relating to Loran's interests, artwork, and writings. Also found are scattered invitations, lecture announcements, postcards, programs, and an advertisement and book jacket for Cézanne's Composition. Exhibition catalogs, exhibition announcements and posters related to other artists can be found, including Cézanne, Hans Hofmann, and Roy Lichtenstein.
  - Advertisements, 1943-1960s (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Art Supplies, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Artists' Oil Paints, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Artists' Pigments, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Auction Catalogs, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Auction Catalogs, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Auction Catalogs, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Auction Catalogs, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Bibliography, 1970s (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Book Catalogs, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Book Jackets, 1925-1969; (see also Box 14) (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Bookmark, 1930s-1950s (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Bookplate, circa 1944 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Calendars, 1944-1983 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Catalog of Exhibitions, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - CézanneDiagrams, circa 1943 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - CézanneIn Perspective, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Cézanne's Composition Materials, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Clippings, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Clippings, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Clippings, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Clippings, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Clippings, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Clippings, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Clippings, 1939; (see also Box 14) (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Clippings, circa 1930s (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Clippings, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Clippings, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Clippings, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Clippings, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Clippings, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Clippings, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Clippings, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Clippings, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Clippings, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Clippings, circa 1940s (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Clippings, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Clippings, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Clippings, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Clippings, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Clippings, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - Clippings, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Clippings, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - Clippings, circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Clippings, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Clippings, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Clippings, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Clippings, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - Clippings, 1965; (see also Box 14) (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Clippings, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Clippings, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Clippings, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Clippings, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - Clippings, 1960s (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Clippings, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Clippings, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Clippings, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Clippings, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Clippings, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Clippings, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Clippings, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Clippings, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Clippings, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Clippings, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - Clippings, circa 1970s (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - Clippings, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - Clippings, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - Clippings, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - Clippings, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 99)
  - Clippings, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 100)
  - Clippings, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 101)
  - Clippings, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 102)
  - Clippings, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 103)
  - Clippings, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 104)
  - Clippings, circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 105)
  - Clippings, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 106)
  - Clippings, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 107)
  - Clippings, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 108)
  - Clippings, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 109)
  - Clippings, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 110)
  - Clippings, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 111)
  - Clippings, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 112)
  - Clippings, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 113)
  - Competition Announcements, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Conservation and Preservation Publications, 1960-1970s (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Dowicil 100, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - East of the Atlantic, West of the Congo, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Enduring Colors For the Artist, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1933-1994 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1931-1938 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1938-1939 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1940-1941; (see also Box 14) (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1941-1942; (see also Box 14) (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1943-1944; (see also Box 14) (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1945-1946; (see also Box 14) (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1946-1947; (see also Box 14) (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1948; (see also Box 14) (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1948-1949; (see also Box 14) (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1950; (see also Box 14) (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1950-1951; (see also Box 14) (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1952-1953; (see also Box 14) (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1954-1956; (see also Box 14) (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1956-1957; (see also Box 14) (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1958; (see also Box 14) (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1959-1960; (see also Box 14) (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1961-1964 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Exhibition Announcements: Others, A-H, 1961-1993 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Exhibition Announcements: Others, H-Z, 1954-1993 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Exhibition Catalogs: Others, A-C, 1934-1990 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Exhibition Catalogs: Others, F-K, 1958-1989 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition Catalogs: Others, L-P, 1959-1993 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Exhibition Catalogs: Others, P-W, 1950-1990 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Eye Chart, circa 1930s-1960s (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Funeral Program, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Hans Hofmann, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Hans Hofmann: the Renate Series, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Invitations, 1966-1983 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Itineraires de Cézanne, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Joseph M. Bransten 1900-1980 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Landscapes, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Lecture Announcements, circa 1970s-1988 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Liquitex, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Lois Wilde Hartshorne, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Maps, circa 1930s-1960s (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Music Programs, circa 1960s (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Newsletter, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Off-Prints, 1935-1968 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Opening Address at Rothko Chapel, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Pamphlets, 1955-circa 1960s (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - A Personal View Of the Rothko Chapel and Newman Obelisk, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Postcards: Artwork, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Postcards: Locations, circa 1930s-1960s; (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 23-24)
  - Postcards: With Locations, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Posters, 1958-1991; (see also Box 14) (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Press Releases, 1940s-1994 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Prospectus, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Registration Form, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Reproductions of Artwork, circa 1940s-1970s (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Reproductions of Artwork: Others, circa 1930s-1970s; (see also Box 14) (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Technical Facts For the Artist, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - This is Painted Desert, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - What is Art [excerpt], circa 1950s-1960s (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Winter Channels, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - XXX Plus One, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Book Jacket, 1943; Cézanne's Composition (Box 14 (sol), Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1939; (see also Box 8) (Box 14 (sol), Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1965; (see also Box 8) (Box 14 (sol), Folder 4)
  - Crystal Forms, 1960s (Box 14 (sol), Folder 5)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, circa 1940s-1960; (see also Box 9) (Box 14 (sol), Folder 6)
  - Posters, 1964; (see also Box 10) (Box 14 (sol), Folder 7)
  - Posters, 1967; (see also Box 10) (Box 14 (sol), Folder 8)
  - Reproduction of Artwork: Others, circa 1950s-1960s; (see also Box 10) (Box 14 (sol), Folder 9)
- Photographs, 1910s-1990s; Series 7; (Boxes 10-12, 14; 2.5 linear feet)